Saturday, July 18th
Well, good morning!
Good morning.
Good morning, though it is pretty late.
I overslept. Oh, you don't have to do that.
It's no trouble at all.
Thank you very much.
Huh?
Saki is still in bed.
Is she? That's unusual.
Seems she was up late studying.
I swear, she's gonna catch a cold sleeping
with her tummy exposed and the AC on.
It looks like it's going to be
another hot summer.
It sure does.
Episode 5 "A Late Show and theReal Deal"
Hey, do we have any other copies of this?
A Rift in
the Blue Night
Animated
Feature
Um, there's just one more.
Oh, is that all they sent us?
I guess that's not enough to make a stack.
Want to shelve them upright?
Hmm, I'd rather not have to do that.
A Rift in the Blue Night
Huh. Is it a book you like?
Oh, it was adapted into a movie.
"Just once a week in the park at midnight,
a boy sees a girl carrying an old violin.
Men from her past are chasing her.
While unraveling the mystery of the violin,
the boy joins the girl for a journey
through time and space.
What is the sound that
will change their future?
Over 2 million copies sold
When you finish reading,
you'll want to stand up and yell,
Coming to theaters
'Bravo!'"
It sounds interesting.
How about we shelve them facing outward?
I guess that would work.
A Rift in the Blue Night
A girl he can only meet
at midnight. What is that fateful sound
drawing them together?
The movie's still playing, isn't it?
It ends tomorrow. They'll be
replacing it with summer movies.
Oh, I see.
I've got work...
Want to catch a late show
after we finish up tonight?
A late show? Tonight?
I get off at eight o'clock. Don't you, too?
Well, yeah.
Saturday nights are perfect
for fooling around!
Phrasing!
What? We're just going to see a movie.
All right.
I'm interested, too. Shall we?
I'll message my parents later.
My, what a wholesome high schooler you are!
Uh, you were a high schooler
not that long ago yourself.
College students are proper adults, though.
Are you saying you're unwholesome now?
Phrasing!
But you know, if you're
going to message anyone,
isn't there someone more
important than your parents?
Huh? Who do you mean?
Your little sister.
Won't she be worried about you?
Worried about me? No, I doubt that.
Huh.
A Rift in the Blue Night
Is that right?
What do you want to drink?
A Diet Coke!
What's so funny?
The typical movie popcorn and Diet Coke?
I like to stick to the classics.
All right, then. Would you like any flavoring?
Caramel all the way!
Huh. Of course.
Hey!
A big bucket! You read my mind, sonny.
Is it too much?
Well, you're gonna have some too, right?
I don't usually snack during the movie.
Go ahead and eat as much as you want.
Don't be like that. Let's eat it together.
Okay, I'll have a little.
Up and—
Ow, ow...
There's a girl I can only see at night.
I need you to take care of this for me.
Huh? Why me?
Even if I die, the instrument must live on.
It can't fall into the hands of those men.
What men?
Please! I only have six months left.
Wait! Why only six months?
The truth is, I...
There you are.
This way!
What's this all about?
My violin is really, really old.
I don't know why, but those men
give off the same kind of smell.
They reek of old age?
No! And that's rude to my violin!
Ouch!
It's okay.
No, it isn't.
I've done all I could.
That's a lie.
I can tell you're lying.
Isn't there someplace special
you wanted to see at the end?
There must be. I mean, isn't that
what you've been searching for?
I want... I want to see it with you!
Let's go.
Together. There's still time if we leave now.
Okay.
I owe you one for walking me back.
Huh? It's not that big a deal.
It's okay. I want to repay you.
Good evening. It sure is hot today.
It sure is.
Are you sure all you want is a drink?
Yes.
Want me to open it?
I can get it.
Wow, you sure are handy.
Oh, shoot! I should have recorded that
with my phone so the whole world could see!
I'd ask that you respect my privacy.
I bet it would get tons of views, though.
It's still nothing to brag about.
You're really fun, and you're so kind to me.
What's gotten into you?
Well...
Listen, my sweet junior.
There's something I have to tell you.
Something you have to tell me?
Yes. Something I want you to know.
The truth is, I...
only have six months left to live.
I can tell you're lying.
Let's go. There's still time if we leave now.
I—
Good evening. It sure is hot today.
Senpai?
I was just thinking that the view from here
is exactly like that park in the movie.
Oh. Yeah, it does look like that.
Unfortunately, though, I can't time travel.
I guess not. Can I toss that can for you?
Thank you.
Should we get going?
Oh, sure.
I'll be okay from here.
Bye!
Yeah.
Thanks again for that
music you told me about.
It made Ayase-san really happy, too.
Be sure to give your dear sister my regards.
Up and—
Ow, ow...
Hey, someone put a blanket over
me last night. Was that you?
Sunday, July 19th
Oh. Well, yeah.
I thought so.
It wouldn't be good if you got
sick before your retest.
Yeah, you're right. Thanks.
You don't need to thank me for that.
Didn't you go see a movie last night?
Uh... yeah.
It's called A Rift in the Blue Night.
I think I saw a commercial for that. How was it?
It was really good. Actually,
I highly recommend that you see it.
Not until after the test.
I know.
If it's based on a book,
maybe I'll read that instead.
It might even help my literature grade.
Good point.
So, are you dating that senpai at work?
Things aren't like that between us.
They're not?
She's just a coworker.
Huh.
She likes books, too,
so we have a lot to talk about.
You do read a lot of books, Asamura-kun.
I should start reading more, too.
I'd love to get another friend into books.
But you should focus on your test for now.
Huh?
Oh, yeah.
Hello, my sweet junior!
Senpai...
Are you restocking?
Yes. Would you give me a hand?
Sure.
Do you think this is good?
Yeah.
Oh, that girl looks like she's looking
for something. I'll be right back.
Can I help you find anything?
Huh? Oh, yes, a book.
Ayase-san?
Oh, you're looking for a book?
Please, allow me to be of assistance!
I'd love to help!
Sure. Thank you very much.
Just leave it to me!
Say, aren't you his little sister?
Um, yes. And you are?
Hey!
Yomiuri Shiori. Nice to meet you.
You're every bit as pretty as he said you were!
Adorable, just adorable!
You're acting like some drunk guy at a bar.
Um, Asamura-kun,
I'm looking for a study guide.
If you want a study guide—
Oh, and also the novel version
of the movie you saw yesterday.
Oh, are you interested in the movie, too?
If so, there's a late show we could—
Ayase-san needs to study.
Don't try to lead her down the path of evil.
But the flowers along the path of evil are
beautiful because they're watered with blood!
That's clearly inefficient.
Flowers grown properly with water
and sunlight will always be superior.
We don't have time for this pointless
chit-chat on the clock, my sweet junior!
Our top priority should be pointing our
lost customer in the right direction!
So anyway, my sweet junior's little sister,
about that book you're looking for...
It's Saki. Ayase Saki.
Ayase?
I don't mind if you call me Asamura Saki,
but that might make things confusing.
Please just use my given name.
Okay, then. I'll call you Saki-chan.
Now, you're looking for a study guide
and the novel the movie's based on, right?
Yes. Also, Asamura-kun, are there any
other books you'd recommend for me?
You want my recommendations?
Since you read so many books,
I figure you must know some good ones.
It'll help me study, too.
Oh... Okay, I'll pick something for you.
Is working the register hard?
Well, kind of.
It's an endless string of brief conversations
with people you don't necessarily level with.
It isn't really that scary, though.
Next is the study guide, right?
Now Hiring Part-Timers!
If you're interested in books and publishing, why not come work with us?
Job Details
Duties: Sales, register, stocking, and inventory
No prior knowledge required
Open Positions: 3
Hours:
Schedule negotiable
Days: 2 to 4 days a week
Looking for cheery, energetic individuals. Ask an employee for details.
Take that escalator down one floor.
They'll be on the shelf on the right.
Okay. Thanks for taking the time to help me.
I'll grab one and head home.
Okay.
That apron looks good on you.
You sure are fast.
Well, I'm used to it.
Yuta-kun is pretty quick, too.
Yuta-kun? Oh, Asamura-kun?
Stop Shoplifting!
I always call him my sweet junior, though.
Okay. Here you go.
Thank you very much.
No, thank you!
And for you, Saki-chan, one smile on the house!
Rewards Points Promotion
Earn up to 30%
Potato Salad
Wow!
Your little sister was really cute!
You're still talking about her?
At my age, if you don't maintain a
healthy intake of young girl extract,
you simply start to shrivel up.
You aren't that much older than her.
There's a world of difference between
high school and college students.
You just don't get it, my sweet junior.
I really doubt I ever will.
And Saki-chan's pure and innocent reactions...
My sweet junior, she might be the real deal.
Real deal?
That's right.
Well, I don't know...
You don't? Really?
Ayase-san is still my little sister.
Episode 6 "Sweet 'n' Sour Pork and Rain"